the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
Eric Schmidt he was the CEO of Google
Eric Sc​​hmidt 他是 Google 的首席执行官
for 10 years and a chairman for six more
10年 和 六个 主席
guiding the company through an
指导公司通过
incredible period of growth and a series
令人难以置信的成长期和一系列
of world-changing innovations he is one
他是一个改变世界的创新
of the most impactful leaders in the era
这个时代 最有影响力的领导者
of the Internet and the powerful voice
互联网和 强大的声音
for the promise of technology in our
为了我们的技术承诺
society it was truly an honor to speak
社会是真正说话的荣誉
with him as part of the MIT course on
与他一起参加麻省理工学院的课程
artificial general intelligence and the
人工智能和人工智能
artificial intelligence podcast and now
人工智能播客和现在
here's my conversation with Eric Schmidt
这是我与Eric Sc​​hmidt的对话
what was the first moment when you fell
你倒下 的 第一 刻 是什么 时候
in love with technology I grew up in the
爱上 了技术， 我 在这里长大
1960s as a boy where every boy wanted to
20世纪60年代，每个男孩都想成为一个男孩
be an astronaut and part of the space
成为宇航员和 空间的 一部分
program so like everyone else of my age
程序就像我这个年龄的其他人一样
we would go out to the cow pasture
我们会去奶牛牧场
behind my house which was literally a
我家后面的字面意思是
cow pasture and we would shoot model
牛牧场，我们会 拍模特
rockets off and that I think is the
火箭关闭，我认为是
beginning and of course generationally
开始，当然是世代相传
today it would be video games and all
今天它将是视频游戏和所有
the amazing things that you can do
你可以 做 的惊人的事情
online with computers there's a
在线与电脑有一个
transformative inspiring aspect of
改革的鼓舞人心的方面
science and math that maybe Rockets
可能是火箭队的科学和数学
would bring wood in stone and
会带来石头和石头
individuals you've mentioned yesterday
你昨天提到过的人
that eighth grade math is where the
那 八 年级的数学是哪里的
journey through mathematical universe
通过数学宇宙的旅程
diverges for many people it's this fork
对于很多人来说，这是分叉
in the road way there's a professor of
在路上有一位教授
math a Buckley Edward Frenkel he I'm not
数学一 巴克利爱德华弗兰克尔他我不是
sure of you familiar with him I am he
你肯定熟悉他 我是他
has written this amazing book I
写了这本神奇的书我
recommend to everybody called love and
推荐给所有人称之为爱情
math to my favorite word's
数学到我最喜欢的 单词
he says that if if painting was taught
他说，如果画画是教的话
like math then students would be asked
像数学一样，学生会被问到
to paint a fence just his analogy of
画一个围栏 只是 他的比喻
essentially how math is taught and you
本质上是如何教授数学和你
never get a chance to discover the
永远不会有机会发现
beauty of the art of painting or the
美丽的 绘画艺术或
beauty of the art of math so how when
数学艺术的美丽如何
and where did you discover that beauty
和你在哪里 发现的美
I think what happens with people like
我想人们会喜欢什么
myself is that your math enabled pretty
我自己就是你的数学能力很好
early and all of a sudden you discover
很早就 突然 发现了
that you can use that to discover new
你可以用它来发现新的
insights the great scientists will all
洞察伟大科学家的一切
tell a story the men and women who are
讲一个故事谁是男人和女人
fantastic today it's somewhere when they
太棒了今天它们在某个地方
were in high school or in college they
他们在高中或 大学
discovered that they could discover
发现他们可以发现
something themselves and that sense of
事物本身 和那种感觉
building something of having an impact
建立一些 有影响力的 东西
that you own drives knowledge
你拥有驱动知识
acquisition and learning in my case he
在我的案例中获得和学习 他
was programming and the notion that I
编程和我的想法
could build things that had not existed
可以建立一个 已 不存在的东西
that I had built that had my name on it
我已经建立了 有我的名字就 可以 了
and this was before open-source but you
这是在开源之前， 但 你
could think of it as open source
可以把 它 想象 成 开源
contributions so today if I were a 16 or
如果我是 16岁或以上 ，今天的 贡献
17 year old boy I'm sure that I would
17岁的男孩我敢肯定
aspire as a computer scientist to make a
渴望作为一名计算机科学家做出
contribution like the open-source heroes
贡献像开源英雄
of the world today that would be what
当今世界 将是什么
will be driving me and I'd be trying and
会 驱使我， 我会 努力的
learning and making mistakes and so
学习和犯错误等等
forth in the ways that it works the
第四，它 的 工作方式
repository that represent that github
表示 该github的 存储库
represents and that open-source
代表和开源
libraries represent is an enormous Bank
图书馆代表的是一个巨大的银行
of knowledge of all of the people who
所有的 人 的知识是谁
are doing that and one of the lessons
正在做这个和其中一个 课程
that I learned at Google was that the
我在谷歌学到的是那个
world is a very big place there's an
世界是一个非常 大的地方 有一个
awful lot of smart people and awful lot
可怕的很多聪明的人以及非常多 的
of them are underutilized so here's an
张师傅没有得到充分利用所以这里是一个
opportunity for example building parts
例如建筑 构件机会
of programs building new ideas to
建立新想法 的 计划
contribute to the greater of society so
为社会做出贡献
in that moment in the seventies the the
在七十年代那一刻
inspiring moment where there was nothing
没有任何东西的鼓舞人心的时刻
and then you created something through
然后 你 通过 创造了 一些东西
programming that magical moment so in
编程那个神奇的 时刻
1975 I think you've created a program
1975我想你已经创建了一个程序
called Lex which I especially like
我特别 喜欢 Lex
because my name is Lex so thank you
因为我的名字是Lex 所以谢谢 你
thank you for creating a brand that
谢谢你创造了一个品牌
established a reputation this long
这么长时间建立了声誉
lasting reliable and has a big impact on
持久可靠并对其 产生重大影响
the world and still used today so thank
世界，今天仍然使用，所以谢谢
you for that but more seriously in that
你为此， 但更 严肃的是
time in the 70s as an engineer personal
作为工程师个人在70年代的时间
computers were being born do you think
电脑 正在 诞生，你认为
you'll be able to predict the 80s 90s
你将能够预测 80年代90年代
and the arts
和 艺术
of what computers would go I'm sure I
什么电脑会去我肯定我
could not and would not have gotten it
不能，也不会 得到它
right
对
I was the beneficiary of the great work
我是这项伟大工作的受益者
of many many people who saw it clearer
很多人看到它 更清楚
than I did with Lex I worked with a
我和Lex一起工作过
fella named Michael Lesk who was my
我 叫 迈克尔莱斯克的 家伙 是我的
supervisor and he essentially helped me
主管， 他基本上 帮助了我
architect and deliver a system that's
建筑师和交付系统， 这是
still in use today
今天 还在使用
after that I worked at Xerox Palo Alto
之后我在Xerox Palo Alto工作
Research Center where the Alto was
Alto所在的研究中心
invented and the Alto is the predecessor
发明和奥拓 是前身
of the modern personal computer or
现代个人电脑 或
Macintosh and so forth and the Altos
Macintosh 等等和Altos
were very rare and I had to drive an
是非常罕见的，我不得不开车
hour from Berkeley to go use them but I
伯克利小时去使用它们，但 我
made a point of skipping classes and
提到了跳过课程的重点
doing whatever it took to have access to
尽一切可能获得 访问权限
this extraordinary achievement I knew
我知道这个非凡的成就
that they were consequential what I did
他们是我所做的事情
not understand was scaling I did not
不明白是缩放 我没有
understand what would happen when you
了解当你会发生什么
had a hundred million as opposed to a
有一亿而不是一个
hundred and so the since then and I have
从那时起我就有一百多个
learned the benefit of scale I always
我总是学到规模的好处
look for things which are going to scale
寻找可扩展的东西
to platforms right so mobile phones
平台就是这样的手机
Android all those things there are the
Android 所有那些东西都有
world is a numerous there are many many
世界是众多，有很多
people in the world people really have
人们真正拥有 世界上的 人
needs they really will use these
需要他们真的会使用这些
platforms and you can build big
平台 ，你可以建立大
businesses on top of them so it's
在他们之上的企业所以它是
interesting so when you see a piece of
很有趣所以当 你看到一块
technology now you think what will this
技术 现在你想到 这将是什么
technology look like when it's in the
技术看起来就像是在它的时候
hands of a billion people that's right
十亿人的手是正确的
so an example would be that the market
这样的例子是 ，市场
is so competitive now that if you can't
现在如此竞争如果你不能
figure out a way for something to have a
想办法 让事情变得更好
million users or a billion users it
百万用户 或十亿用户吧
probably is not going to be successful
可能不会 成功
because something else will become the
因为别的东西 会成为
general platform and your idea will
一般平台和你的想法会
become a lost idea or a specialized
成为一个失去的想法或专业
service with relatively few users so
用户相对较少的服务
it's a path to generality it's a path to
这是通向它的道路
general platform use it's a path to
通用平台使用它是一条路径
broad applicability now there are plenty
广泛的适用性现在有很多
of good businesses that are tiny so
良好的企业，是如此的小
luxury goods for example but if you want
例如奢侈品， 但如果你想
to have an impact at scale you have to
你 必须要有 规模的影响
look for things which are of common
寻找常见的东西
value common pricing common distribution
价值共同定价共同分配
and self common problems the problems
和自己常见的问题
that everyone has and by the way people
每个人都有和一路人
have lots of problems information
有很多问题的信息
medicine health education
医学健康教育
so forth work on those problems like you
所以就像你这样的问题
said your big fan of the middle class
你 是中产阶级的 忠实粉丝
because there's so many of them there's
因为那里有很多
so many of them by definition so any
根据 定义，这么多都是 如此
product any any thing that has a huge
产品任何 有巨大的 东西
impact it improves their lives as a
影响 它改善了他们的生活
great business decision it's just good
伟大的商业决策，这是好的
for society and there's nothing wrong
为社会而且没有错
with starting off in the high end as
从 高端 开始
long as you have a plan to get to the
只要你有一个 计划去 的
middle class there's nothing wrong with
中产阶级 有什么错与
starting with a specialized market in
从 一个专门的市场 开始
order to learn and to build and to fund
为了学习，建立和资助
things so you start a luxury market to
事情于是你开始奢侈品市场
build a general purpose market but if
建立一个通用市场，但如果
you define yourself as only a narrow
你把自己定义 为一个狭窄的
market someone else can come along with
市场上有别人可以相处
a general purpose market that can push
一个可以推动的通用市场
you to the corner can restrict the scale
你到角落可以限制 规模
of operation can force you to be a
操作可以迫使你成为一个
lesser impact than you might be so it's
比你可能的影响小。 所以它是
very important to think in terms of
在思考 方面 非常重要
broad businesses and broad impact even
广泛的业务和广泛的影响甚至
if you start in a little corner
如果你从一个 小角落 开始
somewhere so as you look to the
所以在你看的时候
seventies but also in the decades to
七十年代 也要在几十年内到
come and you saw computers did you see
来，你看到电脑了吗？
them as tools or was there a little
他们作为工具还是有一点点
element of another entity I remember a
我记得 的另一个 实体的元素
quote saying AI began with our dream to
引用人工智能开始于我们的梦想
create the gods is there a feeling when
创造众神 是否有一种感觉
you wrote that program that you were
你写了那个程序
creating another entity giving life to
创造另一个赋予生命的实体
something I wish I could say otherwise
这是我希望我可以说 ，否则
but I simply found the technology
但我只是找到了这项技术
platforms so exciting that's what I was
平台如此令人兴奋，这就是我
focused on I think the majority of the
专注于我认为多数 人的
people that I've worked with and there
我已经 与有 工作的人
are a few exceptions Steve Jobs being an
史蒂夫乔布斯是一个例外
example really saw this as a great
例子真的看到这 是一个 伟大的
technological play I think relatively
技术发挥我认为 相对而言
few of the technical people understood
很少 有技术人员理解
the scale of its impact so I used NC P
其影响的规模因此我使用了NC P.
which is a predecessor to tcp/ip it just
这是一个前辈对TCP / IP协议 ，它只是
made sense to connect things we didn't
连接我们没有的东西是有意义的
think of it in terms of the internet and
在互联网的角度来考虑它，
then companies and then Facebook and
然后公司然后Facebook 和
then Twitter and then you know politics
那么Twitter然后你就会了解政治
and so forth we never did that build we
等我们从来没有做过我们的建设
didn't have that vision and I think most
没有那个愿景，我 认为最多
people it's a rare person who can see
人是一个可以看到的罕见的人
compounding at scale most people can see
大多数人都可以看到大规模复合
if you ask people to predict the future
如果你要求人们预测未来
they'll say they'll give you an answer
他们会说他们会给你答案
of six to nine months or twelve months
的 六到 九个月或 12个月
because that's about as far as people
因为这就像人一样
can imagine but there's an old saying
可以想象， 但有一句老话
which actually was attributed to a
实际上归因于一个
professor at MIT a long time ago that we
很久以前麻省理工学院的教授说我们
overestimate what can be done in one
过高估计可以在 一个人 做什么
year and we underestimate what can be
一年， 我们低估了可能是什么
done in a decade
在十年内完成
and there's a great deal of evidence
并且有大量证据
that these core platforms at hardware
这些核心平台在硬件上
and software take a decade right
和软件需要十年的时间
so think about self-driving cars
想想自动驾驶汽车
self-driving cars were thought about in
人们开始考虑自动驾驶汽车
the 90s there were projects around them
90年代周围有项目
the first DARPA Challenger and challenge
第一个DARPA 挑战者和 挑战
was roughly 2004 so that's roughly 15
差不多是2004年， 所以大概是15岁
years ago and today we have self-driving
几年前和今天我们 都有自驾车
cars operating in a city in Arizona
在亚利桑那州的一个城市运营的汽车
right it's 15 years and we still have a
这是15年，我们还有 一个
ways to go before they're more generally
在他们更普遍之前要走的路
available so you've spoken about the
你可以这么说的
importance you just talked about
你刚才谈到的重要性
predicting into the future he's spoken
预测他所说的未来
about the importance of thinking 5 years
关于思考 5年 的重要性
ahead and having a plan for those 5
提前为 这5人 制定计划
years the way to say it is that almost
这几年说的方式就 差不多了
everybody has a 1 year plan almost no
每个人都有 一年的计划 几乎 没有
one has a proper 5-year plan and the key
一个人有 一个适当的5年计划和关键
thing to have on a 5-year plan is having
有一个5年计划的是有
a model for what's going to happen under
将要发生什么的 模型
the underlying platforms so here's an
底层平台所以这里是一个
example compute Moore's law as we know
我们知道，例子计算摩尔定律
it the thing that powered improvements
这是推动 改进的因素
in CPUs has largely halted in its
在CPU中，它已基本停止了
traditional shrinking mechanism because
传统的收缩机制因为
the costs have just gotten so high it's
成本却刚刚得到这么高 是
getting harder and harder but there's
越来越难， 但有
plenty of algorithmic improvements and
大量的 算法改进和
specialized Hardware improvements so you
专门的硬件改进，所以你
need to understand the nature of those
需要了解那些的本质
improvements and where they'll go in
改进和他们将进入的地方
order to understand how it will change
以了解它将如何 改变
the platform in the area of network
网络 领域的平台
connectivity what are the gains that are
连通性是什么收益
gonna be possible in wireless it looks
会是可能 的 无线看起来
like there's an enormous expansion of
像有 一个巨大 的 扩张
wireless connectivity at many different
许多不同的无线连接
bands right and that we will primarily
乐队正确，我们将主要
historically I've always thought that we
从历史上看，我一直以为我们
were primarily going to be using fiber
进行了初步将 要使用纤维
but now it looks like we're going to be
但现在看起来 我们会成为
using fiber plus very powerful high
使用纤维加非常强大的高
bandwidth sort of short distance
带宽类 短距离
connectivity to to bridge the last mile
连接到桥接最后一英里
right that's an amazing achievement if
对， 如果这是一个了不起的成就
you know that then you're going to build
你知道那时你要 建造
your systems differently by the way
顺便提一下你的系统
those networks
那些网络
latency properties right because they're
延迟属性是正确的，因为它们是
more symmetric the algorithms feel
算法感觉 更对称
faster for that reason and so when you
因为这个原因更快，所以当你
think about whether there's a fiber or
想想是否有纤维或纤维
just technologies in general so there's
只是技术，所以有
this Barbara wouldn't poem or quote that
这芭芭拉不会写诗或引用 它
I really like it's from the champions of
我真的很喜欢它的冠军
the impossible rather than the slaves of
不可能的 而不是奴隶
the possible that evolution draws its
进化的可能性
creative force so in predicting the next
创造力如此预测 下一个
five years I'd like to talk about the
五年 我想谈谈
impossible and the possible well and
不可能和可能的好
again and again one of the great things
一次又一次 的 伟大事情
about humanity is that we produce
关于人性是我们生产的
dreamers right right we literally have
梦想家右边我们确实有
people who have a vision and a dream
有远见 和 梦想的人
they are if you will disagreeable in the
他们 是，如果你将在不愉快
sense that they disagree with the they
感觉他们不同意他们
disagree with what the sort of zeitgeist
不同意那种时代精神
is they they say there is another way
是他们说他们还有 另一种方式
they have a belief they have a vision if
他们相信他们有远见
you look at science science is always
你总是看科学科学
marked by such people who who went
以这样的人为标志
against some commercial wisdom collected
反对一些商业智慧收集
the knowledge at the time and assembled
当时的知识和组装
it in a way that produced a powerful
它以一种产生强大的方式
platform and you've been amazingly
平台，你一直很惊讶
honest about in an inspiring way about
诚实， 大约一个鼓舞人心的方式
things you've been wrong about
你错了的事情
predicting and you've obviously been
预测，你显然是
right about a lot of things but in this
关于很多 事情，但在此
kind of tension how do you balance as a
那种紧张你怎么平衡作为一个
company in predicting the next five
公司预测未来五年
years the impossible planning for the
几年不可能的计划
impossible so listening to those crazy
不可能 听那些疯狂的人
dreamers letting them do letting them
梦想家让他们放过他们
run away and make make thing possible
逃跑，让 事情 变得 可能
real make it happen and slow you know
真实让它发生，慢慢知道
that's how programmers often think and
这就是程序员经常思考的方式
slowing things down and saying well this
放慢脚步，说得好
is the rational this is the possible the
是 理性这是可能的
pragmatic the dreamer versus the
务实的梦想家与
pragmatist so it's so so it's helpful to
实用主义者， 所以它是如此有用
have a model which including encourages
有一个包括鼓励的模型
a predictable revenue stream as well as
可预测的收入来源以及
the ability to do new things so in
做新事物 ，因此在 能力
Google's case were big enough and well
谷歌的案例足够大而且很好
enough managed and so forth that we have
我们有足够的管理等等
a pretty good sense of what our revenue
一个相当不错的 就是 我们的收入 感
will be for the next year or two at
将 在 未来 一两年内 到达
least for a while and so we have enough
至少有一段时间 ，所以我们有足够的
cash generation
现金产生
that we can make bets and indeed Google
我们可以下注，实际上是谷歌
has become alphabet so the corporation
已成为字母表所以公司
is organized around these bets and these
是围绕这些赌注和这些赌注组织的
in bets are in areas of fundamental
投注属于基本领域
importance to to the world or whether
对世界的重要性或是否
its artificial intelligence medical
它的 人工智能医疗
technology self-driving cars
技术自动驾驶汽车
connectivity through balloons the on and
通过气球连接 和
on and on and there's more coming and
等等，还有更多
more coming so one way you could rest
更多的是你可以休息的方式
this is that the current business is
这就是 目前的业务
successful enough that we have the
我们有足够的成功
luxury of making bets and another one
做 赌注和另外一个豪华
that you could say is that we have the
你 可以说的是 ，我们 有
wisdom of being able to see that a
能够 看到 一个的智慧
corporate structure needs to be created
需要创建公司结构
to enhance the likelihood of the success
增加成功的可能性
of those bets so we essentially turned
那些赌注 让我们基本上转向了
ourselves into a conglomerate of bets
我们自己陷入了一个集团的赌注
and then this underlying corporation
然后这个底层公司
Google which is itself innovative so in
谷歌本身也是创新的
order to pull this off you have to have
为了拉这一关 ， 你必须 有
a bunch of belief systems and one of
一堆信仰系统和一个
them is that you have to have bottoms up
他们是你 必须要 打底
and tops down the bottoms up we call 20%
最重要的是我们称之为20％
time and the idea is that people can
时间和想法是人们 可以
spend 20% of the time on whatever they
花费20％的时间在他们身上
want and the top down is that our
想要和自上而下是我们的
founders in particular have a keen eye
创始人尤其敏锐
on technology and they're reviewing
关于技术和他们正在审查
things constantly so an example would be
不断的事情就是一个例子
they'll hear about an idea or I'll hear
他们会听到一个想法，或者我会听到
about something and it sounds
关于某事 ，它听起来
interesting let's go visit them
有趣的是让我们去拜访他们
and then let's begin to assemble the
然后让我们开始组装
pieces to see if that's possible and if
片段，看看是否 可能 ，如果
you do this long enough you get pretty
你做得这么长， 你会变得漂亮
good at predicting what's likely to work
擅长 预测什么是可能 奏效
so that's that's a beautiful balance
这就是美好的平衡
that struck is this something that
这件事就是这样的
applies at all scale so in the zone
适用于该区域的所有规模
seems to be that Sergey again 15 years
似乎 是 谢尔盖再次 15年
ago it came up with a concept called ten
之前它提出 了 一个名为ten的概念
ten percent of the budget should be on
应该 有 10％的预算
things that are unrelated it was called
被称为无关的东西
seventy twenty ten seventy percent of
百分之 七十二十。 百分之七十
our time on core business twenty percent
我们的核心业务时间百分之二十
on adjacent business and ten percent on
在相邻的业务和百分之十
other and he proved mathematically
另外，他在数学上证明了这一点
course he's a brilliant mathematician
当然，他是一位才华横溢的数学家
that you needed that ten percent right
你需要 百分之十的权利
to make the sum of the growth work and
使增长的总和 工作和
it turns out he was right so getting
事实证明他是对的， 所以得到
into the world of artificial
进入人工世界
you've talked quite extensively and
你谈得非常广泛
effectively to the impact in the near
有效地在附近产生影响
term the positive impact of artificial
术语 人工的积极影响
intelligence whether it's a machine
智能 是否是一台机器
especially machine learning in medical
尤其是医疗机器学习
applications and education and just
应用和教育 ，只是
making information more accessible right
使信息更容易获取
in the AI community there is a kind of
在AI社区有一种
debate so there's the shroud of
辩论所以有它的 骄傲
uncertainty as we face this new world
我们面对这个新世界的不确定性
with artificial intelligence in it and
人工智能 和
there is some people like Elon Musk
有一些人喜欢伊隆马斯克
you've disagreed on at least on the
你至少不同意的
degree of emphasis he places on the
强调程度，他放置 在
existential threat of AI
人工智能的存在威胁
so I've spoken with Stuart Russell Max
所以我和Stuart Russell Max谈过
tegmark who share Elon Musk's view and
tegmark分享了Elon Musk的观点和观点
yoshua bengio Steven Pinker who do not
yoshua bengio Steven Pinker谁没有
and so there's a there's a there's a lot
所以有一个有很多
of very smart people who are thinking
非常聪明的 人 正在思考
about the stuff disagreeing which is
关于那些不同意的东西
really healthy of course so what do you
真的很健康，所以你呢？
think is the healthiest way for the AI
认为是人工智能最健康的方式
community to and and really for the
社区和真正的社区
general public to think about AI and the
一般公众要考虑人工智能和人工智能
concern of the technology being
该技术被关注
mismanaged in some in some kind of way
在某些方面以某种方式管理不善
so the source of Education for the
所以 教育的来源为
general public has been robot killer
普通大众一直 是机器人杀手
movies right and terminator etc and the
电影权和终止等 与
one thing I can assure you were not
有一件事我可以向你保证 不是
building are those kinds of solutions
建筑是那种 解决方案
furthermore if they were to show up
此外，如果他们 出现
someone would notice and unplug them
有人会注意到并拔下它们
right so as exciting as those movies are
右所以令人兴奋，因为那些电影
and they're great movies were the killer
他们是伟大的电影是杀手
robots to start we would find a way to
机器人开始我们会找到一种 方法
to stop them right so I'm not concerned
阻止他们， 所以我不 担心
about that and much of this has to do
关于这一点 ，其中很多 都要做
with the time frame of conversation so
与谈话的时间框架 如此
you can imagine a situation a hundred
你可以想象一百个情况
years from now when the human brain is
从人类大脑开始的几年
fully understood in the next generation
在下一代充分了解
and next generation of brilliant MIT
和 下一代辉煌麻省理工学院
scientists have figured all this out
科学家们已经想到了这一切
we're going to have a large number of
我们将有大量的
ethics questions right around science
关于科学的伦理问题
and thinking and robots and computers
和思考，机器人和计算机
and so forth and so on so it depends on
依此类推，依此 类推
the question of the time
时间 问题
in the next five to ten years we're not
在接下来的五到十年里， 我们 不是
facing those questions what we're facing
面对我们所面临的问题
in the next five to ten years is how do
在未来五到十年内 是怎么做的
we spread this disruptive technology as
我们将这种颠覆性技术传播为
broadly as possible to gain the maximum
尽可能广泛地获得最大值
benefit of of it
它的好处
the primary benefit should be in
主要的 好处 应该 是
healthcare and in education healthcare
医疗保健和教育 保健
because it's obvious we're all the same
因为很明显我们都是一样的
even though we don't we somehow believe
即使我们不以某种方式相信
we're not as a medical matter the fact
事实上我们不是医学问题
that we have big data about our health
我们对我们的健康大数据
will save lives allow us to get you know
将拯救生命让 我们知道你
deal with skin cancer and other cancers
处理皮肤癌和其他癌症
therma logical problems there's people
有逻辑问题的人有
working on psychological diseases and so
致力于心理疾病 等
forth using these techniques I go on and
我继续使用这些技术
on the promise of AI in medicine is
人工智能在医学上的承诺是
extraordinary there are many many
非凡的有很多
companies and startups and funds and
公司和创业公司和基金
solutions and we will all live much
解决方案，我们都会活得很多
better for that the same argument in in
对于那个相同的论点更好
education can you imagine that for each
教育可以 为每个人 设想
generation of child and even adult you
一代孩子甚至成年人
have a tutor educator that's AI based
有一个基于AI的导师教育家
it's not a human but is properly trained
它不是一个人， 而是经过适当的训练
it helps you get smarter helps you
它可以帮助您变得更聪明，帮助您
address your language difficulties or
解决你的语言困难或
your math difficulties or what have you
你的数学困难或你有什么
why don't we focus on those two the
为什么我们不专注于那 两个呢
gains societally of making humans
从社会角度来说，制造 人类
smarter and healthier are enormous right
更聪明，更健康是巨大的权利
and those translate for decades and
那些翻译几十年了
decades and we'll all benefit from them
几十年， 我们都将从中 受益
there are people who are working on AI
有人正在研究人工智能
safety which is the issue that you're
安全是你的问题
describing and there are conversations
描述和有 对话
in the community that should there be
在应该存在的社区中
such problems what should the rules be
这些问题应该是什么规则
like Google for example has announced
比如谷歌已宣布
its policies with respect to AI safety
其有关人工智能安全的政策
which I certainly support and I think
我当然支持并且我认为
most everybody would support and they
大多数人 都会支持他们
make sense right so it helps guide the
有意义的权利 ，因此有助于引导
research but the killer robots are not
研究但杀手机器人不是
arriving this year and they're not even
到了今年，他们 甚至 没有
being built and end on that line of
正在兴建 并在该行 的 结束
thinking is at the time scale in in in
思考是 在时间尺度
this topic or other topics have you
这个主题或其他主题 有你
found it useful on the business side of
发现它在商业 方面 很有用
the intellectual side to think beyond
超越思考的知识分子
five ten years to think 50 years out has
五 十年 思考50年了
it ever been useful or productive our
它曾经有用或富有成效
industry there are essentially no
工业基本上 没有
example
例
50 year predictions that have been
已有 50年的 预测
correct let's review a I write AI which
正确让我们回顾 一下我写的AI
was largely invented here at MIT and a
很大程度上是在麻省理工学院发明 的
couple of other universities in the 1956
1956年 的其他几所大学
1957 1958 the original claims were a
1957 年1958年原始索赔是 一个
decade or two and when I was a PhD
十年或两年 ，当我还是博士
student I studied a I bet and it entered
学生我研究了我 打赌 它进入了
during my looking at it a period which
在我看着它的时期
is known as AI winter which went on for
被称为AI冬天持续了
about thirty years which is a whole
大约三十年 是一个整体
generation of science scientists and a
一代科学家和科学家
whole group of people who didn't make a
人全团谁没有做
lot of progress because the algorithms
很多人 因为算法进展
had not improved and the computers had
没有改进，电脑也没有
not approved it took some brilliant
没有批准它花了一些精彩
mathematicians starting with a fellow
数学家从一个家伙开始
named geoff hinton at toronto and
在 多伦多名为杰夫·辛顿 和
montreal who basically invented this
蒙特利尔谁基本上发明了这个
deep learning model which empowers us
深度学习模式赋予 我们 权力
today those the seminal work there was
今天那些开创性的工作
20 years ago and in the last 10 years
20 年前 和过去 10年
it's become popularized so think about
它变得普及， 所以想一想
the timeframes for that level of
该时间框架 的 该级别
discovery it's very hard to predict many
发现它很难预测很多
people think that we'll be flying around
人们认为我们会飞来飞去
in the equivalent of flying cars who
相当于 飞行汽车的人
knows my own view if I want to go out on
如果我想出去 ， 我就知道自己的 看法
a limb is to say that well we know a
一个肢体就是说 我们知道了
couple of things about 50 years from now
从现在开始 约 50年的 几 件事
we know there'll be more people alive we
我们知道我们会有更多人 活着
know that we'll have to have platforms
知道我们必须 拥有平台
that are more sustainable because the
这是因为更可持续
earth is limited you know in the ways we
地球是有限的， 你知道我们的方式
all know and that the kind of platforms
都知道那种平台
that are gonna get billed will be
正在谈婚论嫁 计费 将是
consistent with the principles that I've
符合我 的原则
described they will be much more
描述他们会更多
empowering of individuals they'll be
赋予他们个人权力
much more sensitive to the ecology
对生态 更加 敏感
because they have to be they just have
因为他们必须是他们的
to be I also think that humans are going
我也认为 人类正在 前进
to be a great deal smarter and I think
我认为，要变得更聪明
they're gonna be a lot smarter because
他们会变得更聪明，因为
of the tools that I've I've discussed
我已经讨论过的工具
with you and of course people who live
与你，当然还有 生活的人
longer a life extension is continuing a
寿命延长的时间越长
pace a baby born today has a reasonable
今天出生的婴儿的步伐是合理的
chance of living to a hundred right
活到一百 权 的机会
which is pretty exciting well past the
这是非常令人兴奋的过去
21st century so we better take care of
21世纪所以我们 更好地照顾
them and you mentioned an interesting
他们和 你 提到了一个有趣的
statistic on some very large percentage
一些非常 大的百分比的 统计数据
sixty seventy percent of people may live
百分之 六 十七 的 人可能活着
in cities today more than half the world
在今天的城市中 ，世界上有一半以上
lives in cities and one of the great
生活 在城市 和伟大的 一个
stories of humanity in the last 20 years
过去 20年 的人性故事
has been the rural to urban migration
从农村到城市的迁移
this is occurred in the United States
这发生在 美国
it's occurred in Europe it's occurring
它发生在欧洲，它正在发生
in Asia and it's occurring in Africa
在亚洲，它发生在非洲
when people move to cities the cities
当 人们搬到 城市 的城市
get more crowded but believe it or not
获得更多的拥挤，但信不信 由你
their health gets better their
他们的健康状况会好转
productivity gets better
生产力变得更好
there are IQ and educational
有智商和教育
capabilities improve so it's good news
能力提高所以这是个好消息
that people are moving the cities but we
人们正在移动 城市，但我们
have to make them livable and safe so
必须使它们宜居和安全
you you first of all you are but you've
你首先是你，但是你
also worked with some of the greatest
也与一些最伟大的人合作
leaders in the history of tech what
科技史上的 领导者 是什么
insights do you draw from the difference
你从这个差异中汲取了什么见解
in leadership styles of yourself Steve
在你自己的领导风格史蒂夫
Jobs Elon Musk Larry Page now the new
Jobs Elon Musk Larry Page 现在是新的
CEO sundar Pichai and others from the I
首席执行官sundar Pichai和我的其他人
would say calm sages to the mad geniuses
会对疯狂的天才说平静的贤者
one of these that I learned as a young
其中一个是我在年轻时学到的
executive is that there is no single
执行官 认为没有单一的
formula for leadership they try to teach
他们试图 教导的 领导公式
one but that's not how it really works
一个，但这不是它真正的作用
there are people who just understand
有些 人只是明白
what they need to do and they need to do
他们需要做什么，他们需要 做什么
it quickly
很快
those teeps people are often
这些teeps 人往往
entrepreneurs they just know and they
他们刚才知道的企业家和 他们
move fast there are other people who are
快速移动还有 其他人
systems thinkers and planners that's
系统思想家和计划者
more Who I am somewhat more conservative
更多我更保守的人
more thorough in execution a little bit
执行得更彻底 一点点
more risk-averse
更厌恶风险
there's also people who are sort of
还有一些人
slightly insane right in the sense that
从某种意义上来说，有点疯狂
they are emphatic and charismatic and
他们是有魅力和魅力的
they feel it and they drive it and so
他们感觉到了，他们驾驶它等等
forth there's no single formula to
那里没有单一的公式
success there is one thing that unifies
成功有一点是 统一的
all of the people that you named which
所有你命名 的人
is very high intelligence right at the
是非常高的情报 在
end of the day the thing that
那天的事情到底是
characterizes all of them is that they
所有这些都是他们的特征
saw the world quicker faster they
他们 更快地看到世界
processed information faster they didn't
他们没有 更快地处理信息
necessarily make the right decisions all
必须做出正确的决定
the time but they were on top of it and
的时间 ，但他们是在 它的 上面 和
the other thing that's interesting about
那是些有趣的 另一 件事
all those people is they all started
所有这些人都是他们都开始了
young so think about Steve Jobs started
年轻人所以想想史蒂夫乔布斯开始
a starting Apple roughly at 18 or 19
一个苹果的起始大概是 18 或 19
think about Bill Gates starting at
想想比尔盖茨的起点
roughly 2021
大约2021年
think about by the time they were 30
想到他们 30岁的时候
Mark Zuckerberg a more a good example at
马克·扎克伯格是 一个更好的例子
1920 by the time they were 30 they had
1920年他们30岁的时候
10 years
10年
at 30 years old they had ten years of
在30 岁，他们有 十多年 的
experience of dealing with people and
与人 打交道的经验 ，
products and shipments and the press and
产品和货物以及新闻和
business and so forth it's incredible
商业等等令人难以置信
how much experience they had compared to
他们相比有多少经验
the rest of us who are busy getting our
我们其余的人忙着我们的
PhDs
博士
yes exactly so we should celebrate these
是的， 所以我们应该庆祝这些
people because they've just had more
人们，因为他们只有更多
life experience right and that helps
生活经验权利和帮助
inform the judgment at the end of the
在结束时 通知 判决
day when you're at the top of these
这一天，当你在这些的顶部
organizations all the easy questions
组织所有简单的问题
have been dealt with right how should we
已经处理好我们应该如何处理
design the buildings where should we put
设计我们应该放置的建筑物
the colors on our product
我们产品 的颜色
what should the Box look like right the
Box应该是什么样的
problems that's why it's so interesting
问题就是为什么它如此 有趣
to be in these rooms the problems that
在这些房间里的​​问题
they face right in terms of the way they
他们面对的方式 正确
operate the way they deal with their
以他们处理他们 的方式运作
employees their customers or innovation
员工他们的客户或创新
are profoundly challenging each of the
正在深刻挑战每个人
companies is demonstrably different
公司明显不同
culturally right they are not in fact
在文化方面，他们事实并非如此
cut of the same they behave differently
切割相同，他们表现不同
based on input their internal cultures
基于输入他们的内部文化
are different their compensation schemes
与他们的补偿 计划不同
are different their values are different
他们的价值观是不同的
so there's proof that diversity works so
所以有证据证明多样性是如此
so one faced with a tough decision in
这样一个面临着一个艰难的决定
need of advice it's been said that the
需要建议 ，有人说过
best thing one can do is to find the
一个人能做的 最好的事情 就是找到
best person in the world who can give
世界上 最好的人 ，可以给予
that advice and find a way to be in a
这个建议并找到一种方法
room with them one on one and ask so
房间与他们 进行一对一的 ，问这么
here we are and let me ask in a
我们在这里，让我问一下
long-winded way I wrote this down in
啰嗦的方式我写下来了
1998 there are many good search engines
1998年有很多优秀的搜索引擎
like us excite AltaVista Infoseek Ask
像我们一样激动AltaVista Infoseek Ask
Jeeves maybe Yahoo even so Google
Jeeves 甚至可能是雅虎
stepped in and disrupted everything they
介入并打乱他们 所有的一切
disrupted the nature of search the
破坏了搜索的本质
nature of our access to information the
我们对信息的访问性质
way we discover new knowledge so now
我们现在发现新知识的方式
it's 2018 actually twenty years later
这是2018 实际上 二十年后
there are many good personal AI
有很多很好的个人AI
assistants including of course the bus
助理，当然包括公共汽车
from Google
来自谷歌
so you've spoken in medical and
所以你说过医疗和
education the impact of such an AI
教育这种AI的影响
assistant could bring so we arrived at
助理可以带来所以我们到了
this question so it's a personal one for
这个问题所以它是个人的
me
我
but I hope my situation represents that
但我希望我的情况能够代表这一点
of many other as we said dreamers and
我们说过梦想家和其他人
the crazy engineers so my whole life
疯狂的工程师，所以我的一生
I've dreamed of creating such an AI
我梦想创造这样一个人工智能
assistant every step I've taken has been
助理我采取的每一步都是
towards that goal now I'm a research
为了实现这一目标，我现在正在研究
scientist in human centered AI here at
以人为本的人工智能科学家
MIT so the next step for me as I sit
麻省理工学院让 我 坐下来 迈出下一步
here so facing my passion is to do what
在这里 面对我的热情是做什么
Larry and Sergey did in 98 this simple
拉里和谢尔盖在98年这么简单
startup and so here's my simple question
启动，所以这是我的简单问题
given the low odds of success the timing
给定的 成功的可能性低的定时
and luck required the countless other
幸运需要无数其他人
factors that can't be controlled or
无法 控制的因素或
predicted which is all the things that
预测哪一切都是 那样的
Larry and Sergey faced is there some
拉里和谢尔盖面临的是一些
calculation some strategy to follow in
计算一些策略来 遵循
this step or do you simply follow the
这一步还是你只需按照
passion just because there's no other
激情只是因为别无他人
choice I think the people who are in
选择我认为是谁的人
universities are always trying to study
大学总是在努力学习
the extraordinarily chaotic nature of
非常混乱的性质
innovation and entrepreneurship my
我的 创新和创业精神
answer is that they didn't have that
答案是他们没有那个
conversation they just did it they
谈话他们只是做 了他们
sensed a moment when in the case of
在这种情况下感觉到了一刻
Google there was all of this data that
谷歌有所有 这些数据的
needed to be organized and they had a
需要组织起来他们有一个
better algorithm they had invented a
他们发明 了一种更好的算法
better way so today with human centered
今天更好的方式，以人 为本
AI which is your area of research there
AI这是你存在 的 研究领域
must be new approaches it's such a big
必须是新的方法它是如此之大
field there must be new approaches
必须 有新的方法
different from what we and others are
与我们和其他人不同
doing there must be startups to fund
在那里做必须有创业公司来资助
there must be research projects to try
必须有研究项目来尝试
there must be graduate students to work
必须有研究生上班
on new approaches here at MIT there are
在此新方法在麻省理工学院 有
people who are looking at learning from
那些正在寻求 学习的人
the standpoint of looking at child
看着孩子 的观点
learning yes right how do children learn
学习是对的，孩子们如何学习
starting at one above another and the
从一个在另一个上方开始
work is fantastic those approaches are
工作是梦幻般的方法 是
different from the approach that most
从 方法不同，大多数
people are taking perhaps that's a bet
人们正在考虑这可能是一个赌注
that you should make or perhaps there's
你应该做或者也许 有
another one but at the end of the day
另一个，但在 一天 结束 时
the successful entrepreneurs are not as
成功的 企业家 并非如此
crazy as they sound they see an
疯狂，因为他们听起来他们看到了
opportunity based on what's happened
基于发生的事情的机会
let's use uber as an example as Travis
让我们用优步作为Travis的例子
tells the story he and his co-founder
讲述他和他的联合创始人的故事
were sitting in Paris and they had this
坐在巴黎和他们有这个
idea because they couldn't get a cab and
想法， 因为他们 无法获得出租车 和
they said we have smartphones and the
他们说我们有 智能手机和智能手机
rest is history so what's the equivalent
休息是历史所以等同于什么
of that Travis Eiffel Tower where is a
那 特拉维斯埃菲尔铁塔，其中一个是
cab moment that you could as an
驾驶室时刻，你可以作为一个
entrepreneur take advantage of whether
企业家利用是否
it's in human centered AI or something
它是以人为中心的人工智能或其他东西
else that's the next great startup and
否则那是下一个伟大的创业公司
the psychology of that moment so when
当那个时刻 的 心理学
Sergey and Larry talk about it
谢尔盖和拉里谈论 它
in listen to a few interviews it's very
听一些采访非常
nonchalant well here's here's the very
在这里很冷静
fascinating web data and here's an
迷人的网络数据，这里是一个
algorithm we have for you know we just
算法我们为您知道我们刚刚
kind of want to play around with that
有点想玩弄那个
data and it seems like that's a really
数据 似乎是真的
nice way to organize this data yeah well
组织这些数据的好方法，好吧
I can say I should say what happened
我可以说我应该说发生了什么
remember is that they were graduate
记得是他们毕业了
students at Stanford and they thought
他们想到 了 斯坦福大学的学生
there's just interesting so they built a
有趣的是他们建造了一个
search engine and they kept it in their
搜索引擎，他们把它保存在他们的
room and they had to get power from the
房间，他们必须 得到电力
room next door because they were using
隔壁的房间，因为 他们正在使用
too much power in the room so they ran
房间里的电量太大，所以他们跑了
an extension cord over yeah yeah and
是的延长线是啊是啊
then they went and they found a house
然后他们去了，他们找到了一所房子
and they had Google world headquarters
他们有Google全球总部
of five people right to start the
五人有权启动
company and they raised a hundred
公司和他们筹集了一百
thousand dollars from Andy bechtolsheim
来自Andy bechtolsheim的一千美元
who was the son founder to do this and
谁是儿子的 创始人做这件事
Dave Chariton and a few others the point
Dave Chariton和其他几个人 的观点
is their beginnings were very simple but
他们的开始很简单但是
they were based on a powerful insight
他们基于强大的洞察力
that is a replicable model for any
这是 任何 一个可复制的 模型
startup it has to be a powerful insight
启动它必须是一个强大的洞察力
the beginnings are simple and there has
开始很简单，有
to be an innovation in in Larry and
拉里和拉里的创新
sergey's case it was PageRank which was
谢尔盖的情况下，它是PageRank的这是
a brilliant idea one of the most cited
一个绝妙的主意被引用最多的一个
papers in in the world today what's the
今天在世界上的论文是什么的
next one so you're one of if I may say
下一个，所以你是 我可能会说的
richest people in the world and yet it
世界上最富有的人，但它
seems that money is simply a side effect
似乎钱只是一种副作用
of your passions and not an inherent
你的激情 而 不是固有的
goal but it's a you're a fascinating
目标， 但这是一个令人着迷的目标
person too
人 也是
ask so much of our society at the
在 这个问题上 问 我们 这么多 社会
individual level and at the company
个人层面 和 公司
level and Nations
水平和国家
is driven by the desire for wealth what
由渴望财富驱动是什么
do you think about this drive and what
你觉得这个 驱动器和什么
have you learned about if I may
你有没有了解我是否可以
romanticize the notion the meaning of
浪漫化这个概念的含义
life having achieved success on so many
生活在这么多人身上取得了成功
dimensions well there have been many
尺寸很好，有 很多
studies of human happiness and above
人类的幸福和上面 的研究
some threshold which is typically
通常是一些门槛
relatively low for this conversation
这次 谈话相对较低
there's no difference in happiness
幸福没有区别
about in money it's the happiness is
关于金钱，这就是幸福
correlated with meaning and purpose a
与意义和目的相关a
sense of family a sense of impact so if
如果 有家庭 意识的影响感
you organize your life assuming you have
你假设有 你的 生活
enough to get around and have a nice
足够四处走走，玩得很开心
home and so forth you'll be far happier
家等等你会更开心
if you figure out what you care about
如果你弄清楚你在乎什么
and work on that it's often being in
并努力 使它 经常 进入
service to others it's great deal of
为 他人 服务 很多
evidence that people are happiest when
证明人们最快乐的时候
they're serving others and not
他们服务他人而 不是 服务他人
themselves this goes directly against
自己这个 直接违背
the sort of press induced excitement
那种压力引起的兴奋
about powerful and wealthy leaders of
关于强大而富有的 领导人
one craft and indeed these are
一个工艺，事实上这些
consequential people but if you are in a
相关的人，但如果你在一个
situation where you've been very
你去过的情况
fortunate as I have you also have to
我很幸运，你也必须这样做
take that as a responsibility and you
把它当成一种责任而你
have to basically work both to educate
必须基本上都在教育
others and give them that opportunity
其他人给他们机会
but also use that wealth to advance
但也要利用这笔财富来推进
human society in my case I'm
在我的情况下，我是人类社会
particularly interested in using the
特别感兴趣的是使用
tools of artificial intelligence and
人工智能 的工具和
machine learning to make society better
机器学习让社会变得更好
I've mentioned education I mentioned
我提到过 我提到 过的教育
inequality and middle class and things
不平等，中产阶级和事物
like this all of which are a passion of
像这样所有这些都是激情的
mine it doesn't matter what you do it
我的你做什么并不重要
matters that you believe in it that it's
你相信 它的重要性
important to you and that your life will
对你很重要，你的生活也会如此
be far more satisfying if you spend your
如果你花费你的话会更令人满意
life doing that I think there's no
生活在做 我认为没有
better place to and then a discussion of
更好的地方 ，然后讨论
the meaning of life Eric thank you so
生命的意义埃里克 谢谢你
very much Thanks
非常感谢
you
您